Finding Aid for Sligh Family Papers 1842-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Charles R. Sligh, Jr. papers
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook no. 1
      - Clippings, 1952 (Box 13)
      - Clippings, 1953 (Box 13)
      - Papers, 1954; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Papers, 1955 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 2
      - Papers, 1953 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 3 (Box 13)
      - Papers
        - 1952 (Box 13)
        - 1953, 4 folders (Box 13)
        - 1954 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 4
      - Papers, 1952 (Box 13)
      - Papers, 1953; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 5
      - Papers
        - 1953 (Box 13)
        - 1954 (Box 13)
        - 1955, 3 folders (Box 13)
        - 1956 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 6
      - Papers
        - 1953 (Box 13)
        - 1955 (Box 13)
        - 1956 (Box 13)
        - 1957 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 7
      - Papers, 1953; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 8
      - World War II homefront activities (Box 13)
      - Scrapbook no. 9
        - Civil air patrol and other World War II activities (Box 13)
      - Scrapbook no. 10
        - Papers, 1938 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 11
      - Furniture business, 1952-1957 (Box 13)
    - Scrapbook no. 12
      - Furniture advertising, 1949-1950 (Box 13)
      - Furniture advertising and publicity, 1953-1954; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - National Association of Manufacturers
    - Printed materials (Box 14)
    - Audio-tapes (Box 14)
      (largely NAM related speeches)
    - Audio-tapes (Box 15)
    - Phonograph records (Box 16)
      (largely NAM related speeches) [see also outsize records stored in phono-record collection]
  - Bound records of Charles R. Sligh, Jr.
    - Sligh Block
      - Account books of tenant payments, 4 volumes (Box 17)
      - Personal cashbooks, 3 volumes (Box 17)
    - Scrapbook concerning personal and business activities, 1946-1948 (Box 17)
    - Scrapbook containing furniture advertising, 1943-1948 (Box 17)
    - Scrapbook concerning waterskiing, 1946-1948 (Box 18)
    - Album concerning Rhode Island Industry's Open House, 1953 (Box 18)
    - Home appraisal: Beechland, Holland, Mich. (Box 18)
    - Letters of condolence and funeral records of mother, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Subject File
    - Congratulatory letters (Box 24)
    - Manufacturers sales tax, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Sligh Realty Company, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Business in Michigan, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - "Code of Conduct" (Box 24)
    - Material on labor relations, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - C.R. Sligh debate with Walter Reuther, 1956 (Box 24)
- Robert L. Sligh
  The Robert L. Sligh series is a small group of materials accessioned in 2013 related to Robert Lewis "Bob" Sligh, the Sligh Furniture Co. President in 1968-1990. This series includes Robert Sligh's certificates of military training (1945-1946), a photocopy of President Ronald Reagan's letter dated March 31 1988, honoring Bob Sligh's contributions to the people of Holland, Michigan. Also included here is Robert L. Sligh's memoir "Memories and reflections"--a detailed account of Sligh Furniture Company's history in the 1950s-1980s.
  - Certificates
    - Culver Military Academy Athletic Association, 1945-1946 (Box 33)
    - Military Training, ROTC, 1946 (Box 33)
  - Letter signed by Ronald Reagan, 1988 (Box 33)
    (photocopy)
  - "Memories and Reflections" memoir (Box 33)
- Sligh Family Business Records
  The fourth series - Sligh Furniture Company and related family businesses - concerns the Clark-Sligh Timber Co., the Grand Rapids Timber Co., the Sligh Furniture Co., the Santiam Timber Corporation, and the Charles R. Sligh Co.. Included here are minutes of the board of directors, legal papers, and miscellaneous reports.
  - Clark-Sligh Timber Company
    - Record book (Box 18)
      - 1907-1943 (Box 18)
      - 1944-1949 (Box 18)
    - Abstracts of Title, Timber estimates, contracts, and deeds (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 18)
  - Grand Rapids Timber Co.
    - Record Book, 1903-1941 (Volume AC)
  - Sligh Furniture Company
    - Minutes of Board of Directors (Box 19)
    - 1880-1948, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Payroll book, 1880-1881 (Box 19)
    - Articles of association and other legal papers (Box 19)
    - Warranty deeds (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 19)
  - Santiam Timber Corporation
    - Incorporation papers (Box 19)
  - Charles R. Sligh Co. (and related firms, including Sligh Lowry Furniture Company)
    - Reports, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous legal documents, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Publicity (Box 20)
    - Historical material collected by F.X. Blouin for centennial history of company (including remembrances of O.W. Lowry) (Box 20)
  - Clark-Sligh Timber Company
    - Record book, 1907-1943 (Box 18)
    - Record book, 1944-1949 (Box 18)
    - Abstracts of Title, Timber estimates, contracts, and deeds (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 18)
  - Grand Rapids Timber Co.
    - Record book (outsize volume), 1903-1941 (Box 18)
  - Sligh Furniture Company (Box 19)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors
      - 1880-1948, 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Payroll book, 1880-1881 (Box 19)
    - Articles of association and other legal papers (Box 19)
    - Warranty deeds (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 19)
  - Santiam Timber Corporation
    - Incorporation papers (Box 19)
  - Charles R. Sligh Co.
    (and related firms, including Sligh Lowry Furniture Company)
    - Reports, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous legal documents, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Publicity (Box 20)
    - Historical material collected by F.X. Blouin for centennial history of company (Box 20)
      (including remembrances of O.W. Lowry)
  - Catalogs
    - 1895 (Box 29)
    - (Bicycles), 1897 (Box 29)
    - 1907-1909 (Box 29)
    - 1910 (Box 29)
    - 1924 (Box 29)
    - 1928 (Box 29)
    - 1930 (Box 29)
    - 1934 (Box 29)
    - 1936 (Box 29)
    - 1938 (Box 29)
    - 1940-1942, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - World War II (Box 29)
    - 1948-1949, 2 folders (Box 29)
    - 1951-1960, 10 folders (Box 29)
    - 1961-1982, 22 folders (Box 30)
    - 1984-1990, 7 folders (Box 30)
    - 1991-1993, 3 folders (Box 31)
    - 1996-1999, 4 folders (Box 31)
    - 2005-2012, 8 folders (Box 31)
    - Catalogs, Outsize
      - (2), Undated (Box 34)
      - 1908 (Box 35)
      - 1909 (Box 35)
      - 1916, 2 volumes (Box 35)
      - 1919 (Box 36)
      - 1928 (Box 36)
      - 1929 (Box 36)
      - 1930 (Box 36)
      - 1932 (Box 36)
      - 1950 (Box 37)
      - 1951 (Box 37)
      - 1959, 2 volumes (Box 37)
  - Publication, Outsize, Michigan Tradesman, September 1927 (Box 37)
  - Minutes
    - (Sligh-Lowry Furniture Company), 1940-1954 (Box 31)
    - 1954-1967(Sligh-Lowry Furniture Company) (Box 31)
    - 1967-1973(Sligh Furniture Company) (Box 31)
    - 1974-1980(Sligh Furniture Company) (Box 31)
  - Certificate, Michigan Centennial Business, circa, 1980 (Box 31)
  - "Excellence in Craftsmanship: In Our Second Century" newspaper supplement., 1980 (Box 31)
  - Publications, Furniture, with mentions of Sligh Furniture Company (Box 31)
  - Sligh Family History
    - "A History and Genealogy of Hans Ulric Schleich of Wiesloch, Germany and South Carolina," by Yancey J. Dickert (Box 32)
      (mother was Annie I. Sligh)
    - "An Oral History with the Sligh Family" (Box 32)
    - "Genealogy of Ancestors of Barbara Bushnell Pelton and Her Husband, Dr. Almon Klumph No. 2," by Richard Amidon Klumph (Box 32)
    - "Grand Rapids Furniture City," by Norma Lewis (Box 32)
    - "Grand Rapids Made" (Box 32)
    - "History of the City of Grand Rapids, Michigan," by Albert Baxter (Box 32)
    - "Holland: Happenings Heroes Hot Shots," by Randall P. Vande Water (Box 32)
    - "Old Grand Rapids" (Box 32)
    - "Roll of the Burgesses or Freeman (and Widows of Freemen), of the Borough of Berwick Upon Tweed,", 1906 (Box 32)
    - "Session Booke of Bonckle...1684 to 1690", 1899 (Box 32)
    - "Session Book of Bunkle and Preston, 1665-1690", 1900 (Box 32)
    - Memoriam, Mrs. Eliza Sligh, January 23, 1892 (Box 32)
    - Notebook, Poems of Charlotte Klumph? (Box 32)
- Newspaper clippings and Scrapbooks
  The Newspaper Clippings and Scrapbooks Series document the activities of various members of the family from 1848-1956. The largest portion of the series concerns the professional and political careers of Charles R. Sligh Sr. and Charles R. Sligh, Jr., in particular their participation in the National Manufacturers Association. The scrapbooks also include significant advertizing material for the various furniture companies the Slighs owned.
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1848-1896, 12 folders (Box 20)
    - 1896 (Box 20)
      (miscellaneous
    - 1897-1915, 22 folders (Box 20)
    - 1916-1923, 35 folders (Box 21)
    - 1924-1926, 26 folders (Box 22)
    - 1927 (Box 22)
      (largely obituaries of Charles Sligh, Sr.)
    - 1928-1943 (Box 22)
    - 1953-1958 (Box 22)
      (largely National Association of Manufacturers)
    - 1952-1955 (Box 22)
      (Republican politics)
    - December 1955 (Box 22)
      (debate with George Meany)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook, concerning water-skiing
      - 1939-1942 (Volume 3)
        [3]>
      - 1946-1950 (Volume 4)
        [4]>
      - 1951-1956 (Volume 5)
        [5]>
    - Scrapbook concerning Guild Galleries, 1946-1949 (Volume 6)
      [6]>
    - Scrapbook containing ads and publicity for Sligh Lowry Furniture, December 1947-May 1953 (Volume 7)
      [7]>
    - Scrapbook containing Charles R. Sligh Company ads and publicity, 1949-1951 (Volume 8)
      [8]>
    - Scrapbook containing Grand Rapids Chair Co. ads and publicity
      - January-October 1949 (Volume 9)
        [9]>
      - June 1951-May 1952 (Volume 10)
        [10]>
      - December 1949-July 1951 (Volume 11)
        [11]>
      - January-September 1953 (Volume 12)
        [12]>
    - Scrapbook concerning "Cross Country" line of furniture
      - January-October 1950 (Volume 13)
        [13]>
      - October 1950-April 1951 (Volume 14)
        [14]>
      - May 1952-January 1953 (Volume 15)
        [15]>
    - Scrapbook concerning Kent County Republican Committee, August 1952-1954 (Volume 16)
      [16]>
    - Scrapbook concerning National Association of Manufacturers activities
      - December 1948-October 1950 (Volume 17)
        [17]>
      - November 1949-November 1950 (Volume 18)
        [18]>
      - July 1950 (Volume B287/9)
        [special location: B287/9]
      - October-November 1950 (Volume B287/9)
        [special location: B287/9]>
      - November-December 1950 (Volume B287/10)
        [special location: B287/10]>
      - November-December 1950 (Volume B287/11)
        [special location: B287/11]>
      - December 1950-January 1951 (Volume B287/11)
      - February-September 1951 (Volume 19)
        [19]>
      - September 1951-March 1952 (Volume 20)
        [20]>
      - 1952-1953 (Volume 21)
        [21]>
      - December 1952-October 1953 (Volume B287/11)
      - December 1952-October 1953 (Volume B287/11)
      - December 1952-April 1953 (Volume B287/9)
      - April-September 1953 (Volume B287/10)
  - Buildings, 1880-1984 (Box 38)
  - Family photos, 1880-2004 (Box 38)
  - Newspaper clippings (22), 1927-1985 (Volume 1)
  - Convertible showroom trailer, 1930s (Box 38)
  - Business professional, 1937-1983 (Box 39)
  - Family photos & business professional, 1940-1982 (Box 39)
  - Family photos & business professional, 1953-1962 (Box 40)
  - Awards, 1968-1985 (Box 40)
  - Holland Rotary Club, 1983 (Box 41)
- National Association of Manufacturers
  - Minutes
    - Executive Committee, 1954; 1958 (Box 23)
    - Board of Directors, 1953-1957; 7 folders (Box 23)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - 1953 (Box 23)
      - 1954
        - January (Box 23)
        - February (Box 23)
        - March (Box 23)
        - April (Box 23)
        - May (Box 23)
        - June (Box 23)
        - July (Box 23)
        - August (Box 23)
        - September (Box 23)
        - October (Box 23)
        - November (Box 23)
        - December (Box 23)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 23)
      - 1957
        - April, 3 folders (Box 23)
        - May (Box 23)
        - June (Box 23)
        - July-August (Box 23)
      - 1959-1962, July-August (Box 23)
    - Public Relations Department
      - circa 1953-1957, 5 folders (Box 23)
    - Radio and Television Department
      - 1954 (Box 23)
      - 1957 (Box 23)
    - National Education Department
      - 1954 (Box 23)
      - 1955 (Box 23)
    - Taxation Committee
      - 1954-1955, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - International Relations Committee
      - 1953-1954 (Box 23)
    - United Business Committee
      - 1957 (Box 23)
    - Finance Committee
      - 1957, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Old Timers Council
      - 1957 (Box 23)
    - New York office
      - 1957 (Box 24)
    - Washington, D.C. office
    - Detroit office
      - 1953-1954 (Box 24)
      - 1957 (Box 24)
    - Kenneth Miller
      - 1953-1954 (Box 24)
      - 1957 (Box 24)
    - Five Year Tax Plan
      - 1956-1957 (Box 24)
- Visual materials
  The Visual Materials series includes Photographs and Films, mainly recordings of television public affairs programs.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs series, 1 linear foot, consists of numerous individual and group portraits of Sligh family members, shots of Sligh Furniture Company factories and workers, and photos documenting Charles Sligh, Jr's. activities on behalf of the National Association of Manufacturers, including photos with President's Eisenhower and Kennedy.
    - Sligh, Charles R., Sr.
      - Family groups (Box 25)
      - Portraits (Box 25)
      - World War I era (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Charles R., Jr.
      - Conference, Amsterdam (Box 25)
      - Conference, Germany (Box 25)
      - Conference, Paris, 1954 (Box 25)
      - Congress of American Industry (Box 25)
      - Events, Miscellaneous (Box 25)
      - Family groups and children (Box 25)
      - Groups, Miscellaneous (Box 25)
      - Meetings, Miscellaneous (Box 25)
      - National Association of Manufacturers (Box 25)
      - National Bible Week, U.S.S. Bennington, 1955 (Box 25)
      - Portraits as child and young man (Box 25)
      - Portraits in middle age (Box 25)
      - Public appearances, Miscellaneous (Box 25)
      - Television and radio interviews (Box 25)
      - Travel (Box 25)
      - Water skiing, 1946-1948 (Box 25)
        (from album)
      - Water skiing, Miscellaneous (Box 25)
      - With Eisenhower (Box 25)
      - With Kennedy (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Edith Clark (2nd wife of Charles R. Sligh Sr.) (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Eliza Wilson (wife of James W. Sligh) (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Gertrude C. (daughter of Charles R. Sligh Sr.) (Box 25)
    - Sligh, James Wilson
      - Family groups and children (Box 25)
      - Military and miscellaneous (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Mary Stowell Conger (1st wife of Charles R. Sligh, Sr.) (Box 25)
    - Sligh, Robert, Army photos (Box 25)
    - Sligh family
      - Houses (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
    - Sligh Furniture Company
      - Factories and people (Box 25)
      - Furniture groups and furniture delivery by air (Box 25)
    - Unidentified lawn bowling group (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous photographs [including view of Sligh Furniture factory] (Box 28)
  - Films
    [all 16 mm., black & white, sound (except as noted)]
    The Films subseries is composed primarily of recordings of television pubic affairs programs on which Charles R. Sligh, Jr. appeared as spokesman for the National Association of Manufacturers or representative of the business community. The programs include several debates with Walter Reuther and George Meany on tax, labor, and other federal policies.
    - "Open Hearing,", July 22, 1951 (Box 26)
      (CBS-TV Charles R. Sligh, Jr. interviewed)
      [30 min.] [film 89]
    - "American Forum of the Air,", September 16, 1951 (Box 26)
      [film 1; VHS viewing copy available]
      [30 min.]
      (NBC-TV. Walter P. Reuther and Charles R. Sligh, Jr. debate "Our National Tax Program")
    - "Perspective,", January 8, 1953 (Box 26)
      (ABC-TV. Bernard Kilgore, president of The Wall Street Journal, and Richard C. Mosher (?) interview Charles R. Sligh, Jr., new president of the National Association of Manufacturers)
      [30 min.] [film 2]
    - "Youth Wants to Know,", February 15, 1953 (Box 26)
      (Moderator Frank Blair. Charles R. Sligh, Jr. is interviewed by an audience of young adults)
      [30 min.] [film 3]
    - "The Kate Smith Show,", February 16, 1953 (Box 26)
      (Charles R. Sligh, Jr. is interviewed about the National Association of Manufacturers on the "Crackerbarrel" segment of the show.)
      [15 min.] [film 4]
    - "American Forum of the Air,", July 5, 1953 (Box 26)
      (NBC-TV. Moderator, Frank Blair. Charles R. Sligh, Jr. and Rep. Herman P. Eberharter debate "A Manufacturers' Excise Tax, Good or Bad")
      [30 min.] [film 5]
    - "Summer School,", August 31, 1953 (Box 27)
      (Charles R. Sligh, Jr. talks about economics to a group of students)
      [30 min.] [film 92]
    - "The American Forum,", December 11, 1955 (Box 27)
      (NBC-TV. Moderator, Stephen McCormick. Panel, Charles R. Sligh, Jr., A. M. Raskin (New York Times), Donald J. Wickham (Farm Bureau). Guest, Walter P. Reuther.)
      [30 min.] [film 6]
    - "American Forum of the Air,", undated (Box 27)
      (NBC-TV. Moderator, Frank Blair. Charles R. Sligh, Jr. is questioned by an audience of women about "What Women Want to Know about a National Sales Tax")
      [30 min.] [film 7]
    - "Man of the Week,", undated (Box 27)
      (CBS-TV. Panel Al Friendly (Washington Post), Bill Shannon (New York Post), Andrew Tully (Scripps-Howard News Service), Ron Cochran (CBS). Guest, Charles R. Sligh, Jr.
      [30 min.] [film 8]
    - "American Forum of the Air,", undated (Box 27)
      NBC-TV. Moderator Ted Granik, Charles R. Sligh, Jr. and Senator O'Mahoney of Wyoming debate "What Tax Program Do We Need"
      [30 min.] [film 9]
    - "Industry on Parade" Charles R. Sligh, Jr. is shown water skiing with skis produced at his factory (Box 27)
      [5 min.] [film 10]
    - "Overlook for 1953" Charles R. Sligh, Jr. previews the year (Box 27)
      [5 min.] [film 11]
    - Untitled films
      - Spencer Allen interviews Charles R. Sligh, Jr. on President Eisenhower's policies (Box 27)
        [5 min.] [film 12]
      - Charles R. Sligh, Jr. at National Association of Manufacturers meeting in Miami (Box 27)
        [5 min., silent] [film 13]
      - Mr. and Mrs. Charles R. Sligh Jr. in Salt Lake City (Box 27)
        [5 min.] [film 14]
- Miscellaneous Outsize material
  - Layouts of furniture advertising (Box 28)
  - Map of Riverside Gardens, Grand Rapids subdivision (Box 28)